

GORAN RIHTER

FRONTEND DEVELOPER goran.rihter@gmail.com Croatia, Zagreb (willing to relocate) +385 91 908 7486

in /goranrihter

/goranrihter

SUMMARY

I'm a Frontend Developer, ready to put my talents to use. I keep my ambitions simple; keep learning, become more versatile each day. Some technologies I prefer to use are: React, TypeScript, Jest (with React Testing Library) and Sass. Though by my work experience I might not look like a first choice for web de velopment, I'm grateful that path led me back to my passion. The project showcase to the right is outdated by now. As I focused more time on work and improving skills that helped me be more efficient at it. Recently (emphasis on recently:)) I started blogging about frontend and work domain related topics.

SAMPLE WORK

/ Multi-page Design

/<u>Admin UI</u>

/Landing Page

PORTFOLIO / BLOG

/ Portfolio Site
/Blog Site

PROJECTS

CHINGU CODING VOYAGES

- Taking part in remote development coding cohorts that result in working with a team of like-minded Web devs on interesting and challenging projects while learning unknown technologies
- Improving soft skills, including communication, collaboration, and Agile project management, creating impact while leveling-up development skills

VIDEO PRODUCTION PROJECT (COUNTDOWN)

- Contributed in a complete, from ground up making of a 8-minute storytelling video project. It enveloped required planning aspects, filming and editing to mold it into a finished product (Odstevanje / Countdown)
- Designed as a project for a Faculty of Electrical Engineering and Computer Science in Slovenia

ANIMATION WORKSHOP (VANIMA)

- Co-guided an international animation workshop in Varazdin for a week, organizing post workshop events and experiences for all 25+ participants
- Crafted in an outcome was a compilation that showcased work that joined abilities and talents of a large, multilingual, artistic team

EDUCATION

FREECODECAMP BOOTCAMP 2017-ONGOING

 FCC's Front End & Back End Development programs cover about 1200 hours of coursework that include HTML5, CSS, JavaScript and React, Redux, Node, Express, Git, MongoDB and working with APIs

UNIVERSITY NORTH, CROATIA 2009-2011

- Studied about IT and applications, databases & SQL, graphical communication, programming tools, psychology of colors and presentation of information
- Excelled in video editing and illustrating for different media
- Translated highly technical documentation from English to Croatian

SCHOOL OF ELECTRICAL ENGINEERING 2005-2009

- Studied about microprocessors, digital electronics, system software support, diagnostic and maintenance of technical systems, computer service and repair, technical drawing and documenting, precision mechanics and electrical engineering, materials and components
- For my final work, I submitted a 3d model of a female centaur created in 3dsmax

TECHNICAL SKILLS

HTML5 CSS3.0 Scss JavaScript Git React Redux TypeScript

GRAPHIC DESIGN

Photoshop Illustrator 3 ds max

WORK EXPERIENCE

FRONTEND DEVELOPER 06/2018 - PRESENT

- Working on Syskit Point. Through customer feedback and coordination with UX designers, helping in development of additional features of the product.
- Worked on Syskit Insights and Syskit Security Manager; fixing, developing.
- On the job I learned how to work with React, some of its ecosystem, TypeScript and fortified my HTML, CSS and JS skills
- Collaborating in between individual product teams, following the scrum process

FREELANCE DEVELOPER 11/2017 - 06/2018

- Refactored source code down to 15% of its original size for an entire web application
- Updated content on a local business static website and debugged broken features making it current and functional
- Periodic code review and continuous collaboration among teammates in a remote development coding cohorts (Chingu)
- Designing a website for a local business from ground up using current web technologies, making it responsive, compatible and time proof

RETAIL SALES ASSOCIATE ON A CRUISE SHIP 01/2016 - 11/2017

- Overhauled the approach to annual inventory, resulting in 30% faster completion and 5% better final results
- Planned and hosted many promotional events and seminars leading to customer engagement and overall satisfaction, boosting sales and return rate
- Mentored new hires in their respective positions enabling faster familiarization with their work environment and tasks
- Taken part in a competition with our team ranking first in sales performance in 4 specific categories fleetwide

PORTFOLIO SITE

exit(0);